Guide to the Juanita Morris Kreps Papers, 1921-2001 and undated RL.00789
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Speeches Series, 1962-1999 and undated, 18 boxes
  - Chrysler Women's Symposium, 1987 Nov. 10 (Box 46)
  - Economic Justice for Women, Rochester Community Forum, 1987 Nov. 12 (Box 46)
  - National Women's Economic Alliance Foundation- Director's Choice Award, 1987 Dec. 3 (Box 46)
  - Founder's Day- Duke, 1987 Dec. 10 (Box 46)
  - Announcement of "Kreps Chair," 1987 Dec. 11 (Box 46)
  - Governmental and Corporate Strategies in a Global Economy, Rochester Chamber of Commerce, Athena Award in Manhattan, 1988 Jan. 26-27 (Box 47)
  - The Elderly in Today's Economy, Ohio State University, 1988 Apr. 4, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Berry College, Rome, Georgia, 1988 May 4-5 (Box 47)
  - On Work and Success, Northeast Missouri State University commencement, 1988 May 13 (Box 47)
  - Economics for Students and Presidents, Univ. of North Carolina - Charlotte, 1988 Nov. 9-10 (Box 47)
  - Economic Challenges for the 1990s, Fordham Graduate School of Business, 1989 Feb. 27, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Women in Industry, Duke Women's Studies Sesquicentennial Symposium, 1989 Mar. 5 (Box 47)
  - Kodak Management, 1989 Mar. 9 (Box 47)
  - Economic Challenges for the 1990s, Rochester Institute of Technology, 1989 Mar. 10 (Box 47)
  - Berea College, 1989 Apr. 22 (Box 47)
  - Economic Challenges for the 1990s, Buena Vista College, 1989 Sep. 13-14, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Berea College Capital Campaign, 1989 Oct. 28 (Box 47)
  - Career Women: A Salute to Success, Toldeo Women in Business (TWIN), 1989 Nov. 15 (Box 47)
  - The University Today: Managing the Enterprise, Duke's President's Council inaugural seminar, 1989 Nov. 9 (Box 48)
  - Berea College, 1990 Apr. 27 (Box 48)
  - Davidson College commencement, 1990 May 13 (Box 48)
  - Corporate Challenges in the 1990s, Aspen Institute, 1990 Oct. 4 (Box 48)
  - Low Income Housing: The National Equity Fund, Durham Chamber of Commerce and Housing Authority, 1991 Feb. 18 (Box 48)
  - Support for the Arts in Today's Economy, Corporate Council for the Arts, Seattle, Washington, 1991 Jun. 24-25 (Box 48)
  - Kentucky Economic Association, 1991 Oct. 25 (Box 48)
  - Policy Making in a Global Economy, Lenoir-Rhyne College Convocation, 1991 Nov. 4 (Box 48)
  - Berea Luncheon in New York, 1991 Nov. 19 (Box 48)
  - Berea Library Dedication, 1991 Jan. 24 (Box 48)
  - The Economy in 1992: How We Got Here, Duke Campus Club, 1992 Feb. 11 (Box 48)
  - Television Taping with Chancellor Leutze, 1992 Mar. 9 (Box 48)
  - Women Leaders: Why So Few? Milwaukee- Sacajemea Award, 1992 Mar. 3 (Box 48)
  - Taping with Dr. William Friday (aired 1992 Jun. 22), 1992 Apr. 22 (Box 48)
  - Notre Dame, 1992 May 16-17, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Charlotte Country Day School commencement, 1992 Jun. 5 (Box 48)
  - Coming Together in the Midst of Change, Eastern College and Middle Atlantic Placement Associations, 1992 Sep. 14 (Box 48)
  - Public Relations Society of America (NC Chapter), 1992 Sep. 18 (Box 48)
  - Municipal Bond Investors Assurance (MBIA) speech, Tucson, Arizona, 1992 Nov. 11 (Box 48)
  - Duke commencement, 1993 May 16, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - JC Penny Leadership Forum, 1993 May 20 (Box 49)
  - Berea Trustees, 1993 Oct. 21-23 (Box 49)
  - Panel: Partnership between the Duke Endownment and Duke University, 1994 Feb. 12 (Box 49)
  - Kreps Gallery Dedication, 1994 Mar. 19 (Box 49)
  - Can the South Improve Its Workforce? National Humanities, American Issues Forum on the South, 1994 Mar. 25 (Box 49)
  - John and Jane Stephenson's Berea Retirement, 1994 May 21 (Box 49)
  - Thoughts on the Times of Our Lives, Forest at Duke, 2701 Club meeting, 1994 Dec. 12 (Box 49)
  - Public Needs and National Priorities: A Reality Check, women's health care issues speech, Washington Duke Inn, 1995 May 5 (Box 49)
  - Ohio Northern University commencement address, 1995 May 21 (Box 49)
  - Lillywhite Award, Employee Benefits Research Institute (EBRI), 1995 Jun. 22 (Box 49)
  - North Carolina Business Hall of Fame, Sheraton Imperial Hotel, Research Triangle Park, 1995 Nov. 16 (Box 49)
  - The South in the World Economy, Kenan Foundation Panel, 1996 Apr. 27, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - For Women to Make A Difference, National Association of Women Law Enforcement Executives (NAWLEE), 1996 Jul. 20, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - TIAA/CREF Retirement, 1996 Nov. 12 (Box 49)
  - JC Penny Retirement Dinner for Colby Chandler, 1997 May 5, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Duke commencement, 1997 May 18 (Box 49)
  - Berea 1942 Class Reunion, 1997 Jun. 27-29 (cancelled) (Box 50)
  - Women's Studies Lecture Series, 1998 Mar. 7 (Box 50)
  - Introduction: Troubled Leaders, Seminar - National Arts and Humanities Center, UNC-Chapel Hill, 1998 Oct. 24 (Box 50)
  - Berea College, 1999 Apr. 5-6 (Box 50)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs, San Francisco, California, 1999 Jun. 19-20 (Box 50)
  - After 200 Years: A Perspective on Disenchantment, Arden House conference speeches, 1976 and undated (Box 50)
  - Duke commencement speech, undated (Box 50)
  - Home Work, Market Work, and the Allocation of Time, undated (Box 50)
  - Sex and the Scholarly Girl, speech - American Association of University Women (Box 50)
  - The Problem of Being Old, Univ. of Colorado, undated (Box 50)
  - Women: Colleagues or Lovers? Women's Day, Berea, undated (Box 50)
  - Women's Work: Implications for Higher Education, undated (Box 50)
  - The Young, the Old, and the Rest of Us; A 20th Century Dilemma and All Would Live Long, But None Would Be Old, undated (Box 50)
  - Speech ideas, undated (Box 50)
  - Secretary Kreps's past speeches, 1970-1976
    - Unemployment and Underemployment of Women Workers (Box 50)
    - What Shall We Do After We're Liberated? (Box 50)
    - Secretaries, Directors, and Women (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1975-1979, 2 folders
    - The Economy and Higher Education (Box 50)
    - A Look to the 1980s (Box 50)
    - The Economic Status of Women in the United States (Box 50)
    - Human Values, Economic Values, and the Elderly (Box 50)
    - The Young, the Old, and the Rest of Us: A Twentieth Century Dilemma (Box 50)
    - Help! There's A Woman in the Boardroom (Box 50)
    - Learning and Earning: Some New Questions (Box 50)
    - Home Work, Market Work, and the Allocation of Time (Box 50)
    - New Horizons for America's Workers (Box 50)
    - Age, Work, and Income (Box 50)
  - Untitled binder of speeches, undated (Box 50)
- Visual Material Series, 1920s-1980 and undated, 7 boxes
  Contains black and white and some color photographs, photo albums, greeting cards, and post cards. There are some photographs of Kreps as a young girl, as well as a few even earlier images of unidentified individuals and Kreps as a child. Photos titled "Group" along with a number represent images that were originally housed together in envelopes. The three Juanita Morris Kreps scrapbooks are publicity scrapbooks that contain mostly newspaper clippings mentioning her accomplishments and appearances. There are a fair number of images whose subject or source is unknown. Photographs and scrapbooks relating to her cabinet position can be found in the Secretary of Commerce Series. Arranged in original order as received.
  - "Group 2," personal photographs, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - "Group 3" (Box 51)
  - Kreps portraits (Box 51)
  - Secretary of Commerce publicity photos, 8 folders (Box 51)
  - China, undated (Box 52)
  - The European Commission, Brussels, Belgium, 1979 Sep. 24 (Box 52)
  - President Carter bill signing, undated (Box 52)
  - Third Tunisian-American Joint Commission, Tunis, 1979 Mar. 30-31 (Box 52)
  - Beijing, China, undated (Box 52)
  - Japan visit, undated (Box 52)
  - "Group 13" (Box 52)
  - "Group 14" (Box 52)
  - "Group 15" (Box 52)
  - "Group 16" (Box 52)
  - "Group 17" (Box 52)
  - Secretary of Commerce, 1978 Dec. - 1979 Feb., 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Photos from Walter Mondale (Box 52)
  - Pictures used for North Carolina Business Hall of Fame Induction, 1995 Nov. 16, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Warsaw, Poland, 1977 Nov. 28-Dec. 2 (Box 52)
  - "Group 22" (Box 52)
  - Berlin, undated (Box 52)
  - Geneva, undated (Box 52)
  - Unused postcards of China, undated (Box 52)
  - Japan, undated (Box 53)
  - Unused postcard of Saudi Arabia, undated, 4 folders (Box 53)
  - Religious pamphlet, 1976 (Box 53)
  - Greetings, 1979 and undated (Box 53)
  - Woman of the Year party at L'Enfant Plaza, 1978 June 13, 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Visits to foreign countries, undated (Box 53)
  - "Group 31", 3 folders (Box 53)
  - Sheraton photograph, undated (Box 53)
  - Unidentified photo, undated (Box 53)
  - Bryant College Symposium, 1972 (Box 53)
  - "An Evening Together," undated photo album (Box 54)
  - JC Penney photo album [empty] (Box 54)
  - India, 1978 (Box 54)
  - Poland, undated, 2 albums (Box 54)
  - Union Gas Plant Dedication album, Korea, 1977 Sep. 29 (Box 54)
  - Untitled brown album (Box 55)
  - Juanita Morris Kreps scrapbook, 1945-1972 (Box 55)
  - Juanita Morris Kreps scrapbook, 1961-1976 (Box 55)
  - U.S. Merchant Marine Academy graduation album, 1978 Aug. 23 (Box 55)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1979 (Box 55)
  - Unidentified white album, undated (Box 56)
  - Unidentified brown album, undated (Box 56)
  - China, May 1979, 2 albums (Box 56)
  - Secretary of Commerce photos, 1977 Jan. (Box 56)
  - American-Romanian Economic Commission meeting, Washington, D.C., 1977 Nov. (Box 56)
  - Juanita Morris Kreps scrapbook, 1972-1976 (Box 56)
  - U.S. National Trade and Economics Exhibition, Beijing, Peoples' Republic of China, 1980 Nov. 17-28 (Box 56)
  - St. Lawrence University convocation, 1975 Sep. 25 (Box 56)
  - Kreps's Visit to China, May 1979 (Box 56)
  - China, undated (1976?) (Box 56)
  - Japan, 1978 Oct., 2 folders (Box 56)
- Other Files Series, 1946-1984 and undated, 1 box
  Contains materials that fall out of the above series, such as teaching materials and publicity clippings.
  - Agnes Scott College student papers, 1984 (Box 57)
  - Invitation to Kreps's AEA Vice President election ceremony, 1982 (Box 57)
  - Teaching lectures on labor economics, undated (Box 57)
  - The Manpower Report of the President, 1975 (Box 57)
  - Poetry - unknown source, 1969 (Box 57)
  - Publicity clippings, 1946-1976, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Visa, U.S.S.R., 1972 (Box 57)
  - Women - economic issues (articles, papers, newspaper clippings), 1970-1976, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Women - management, vitae on women (in managemement positions), 1976 (Box 57)
  - Women's movement and labor (articles, flyer, Feminist Press Catalog), 1969-1972 (Box 57)